tirebuyer.com 2015-04-24

# Privacy Policy | TireBuyer.com

#### 

$40 off orders $500+: Code **[CARCARE40](http://www.tirebuyer.com/products/NewYear) **  
Excludes Kumho, Fuzion, and Michelin.

#### Effective date: September 18, 2014

 **Notification**

This Privacy Policy governs the information collection and disclosure practices for the Site. When you access, browse or use the Site, information will be collected, transferred, processed, stored, and/or disclosed in accordance with this Privacy Policy. By accessing, browsing, or using the Site, including without limitation purchasing Products via the Site, you expressly consent to the collection, transfer, use, processing and storage of your information, including personal information, as described in this Privacy Policy. Any capitalized terms not defined herein have such definitions as set forth in the Terms of Use Agreement, also posted on the Site. This Privacy Policy is incorporated in the Terms of Use Agreement as if this Privacy Policy was fully set forth therein.

 **Information collection**

 **General.** In general, you can browse the Site without telling us who you are or revealing any personal information about yourself. However, if you wish to create a user account or purchase any of the Products, you will be required to disclose certain information to us. You always have the option to not provide information by choosing not to create a user account or purchase the Products. 

 **Registration.** You are not required to have an account to purchase Products on the Site. However, if desired, you can create a user account with a unique user name and password combination.

If you choose to create a user account, you must provide current, complete, and accurate information to us in connection with your account and/or purchase of Products in order to receive Products from the Site. It is your responsibility to keep the information that you provide to us up to date and we cannot and will not be responsible for any problems or liability that may arise if you do not give us accurate, truthful, or complete information, or if you fail to update the information you give us. During the account set-up process, you are required to give certain contact information, including your name, email address, and in some cases your approximate age. We use this information to contact you about the Products on the Site in which you have expressed interest, and, in the case of your approximate age, to determine whether you are old enough to use the Site. You may have the option to provide additional demographic information (such as vehicle information, income level, location, and gender) to us; we encourage you to submit this information so we can provide you a more personalized experience on the Site. Whenever possible, we indicate which fields are required and which fields are optional.

 **Orders and Payment Processing.** If you purchase Products from us, we request certain personally identifiable information from you on our order form. You must provide contact information (such as name, email, and address) and, where applicable, financial information (such as credit card number, expiration date, and validation number or PayPal account information). We use this information for billing purposes and to fulfill your orders. If we have trouble processing an order, we may use this information to contact you.

We use a third party service provider (currently CyberSouce) to process credit card transactions.  The credit card information that you provide is encrypted and transmitted directly to CyberSource. We do not store your credit card information and do not control and are not responsible for CyberSource or their collection or use of your information. You may find out more on how CyberSource stores and uses your credit card information by accessing the [CyberSource Privacy Policy](https://www.cybersource.com/privacy/). 

We also allow users to pay by using PayPal. If a user chooses to pay by PayPal, the PayPal privacy policy will be accessible on PayPal’s website. 

 **Surveys or contests.** From time to time we may provide you the opportunity to participate in contests or surveys on the Site. If you participate, we will request certain personally identifiable information from you. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and you therefore have a choice whether or not to disclose this information. The requested information typically includes contact information (such as name and email address) and demographic information (such as zip code). We use this information to notify contest winners and to award prizes. We may use a third-party service provider to conduct these surveys or contests.

 **Chats.** We use Vivocha to allow users to participate in chatrooms (“Chats”). We urge you to refrain from providing personally identifiable information in Chats. We have no control of and are not responsible for the information you provide in Chats and all information provided in Chats will be subject to the privacy policy of Vivocha.  You may access Vivocha’s privacy policy by accessing the [Vivocha Privacy Policy](http://www.vivocha.com/privacy.html). 

 **Correspondence.** If you send us personal correspondence, such as emails or letters, or if other users or third parties send us correspondence about your activities or postings on the Site, we may collect such information into a profile specific to you.

 **Information from third parties.** In order to provide certain services to you, we may on occasion supplement the personal information you submitted to us with information from third-party sources.

 **Automatic Information.** As is true of most web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information does not identify individual users and includes, but it is not limited to, (internet protocol (IP) addresses,) browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data (“Non-Personally Identifiable Information”). 

 **Cookies.** A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user's computer for record-keeping purposes. We and our third-party advertising and analytics providers use cookies on the Site to record information about your activities on the Site and to "remember" you when you return to the Site. Some cookies remain on your computer until you delete them others, like session ID cookies, expire when you close your browser.    You may set your browser setting to attempt to reject cookies and you may still use the Site; however, your ability to use some functionality and areas of the Site, such as contests or surveys, will be limited. See the section “Do not track settings” below for more information on how the Site may respond to your browser settings.  We do not control the use of cookies by third parties. See the section on "Third-party advertisers and analytics providers” below and review the privacy policies of each of the third party advertising and analytics providers for more information on third party cookies.  

 **Clear GIFs (web beacons, pixels and bugs).** Clear GIFs (aka web beacons, pixels, web bugs) are tiny graphics with a unique identifier that are used to track the online movements of web users. Unlike cookies, which are stored on a user's computer hard drive, clear GIFs are small graphics that are about the size of the period at the end of the sentence that are embedded invisibly on web pages or in HTML-based emails. We and our third party advertising and analytics providers may place Clear GIFs on our web site that track what other web sites you visit (both before and after visiting the Site).  We and our providers use information obtained from Clear GIFs to analyze the effectiveness of advertisements on our Site as well as on other web sites and to help us improve our business and the Site. We may also use clear GIFs in our HTML-based emails to let us know which emails have been opened by recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns.  We do not control the use of Clear GIFs by third parties. See the section on "Third-party advertisers and analytics providers” below and review the privacy policies of each of the third party providers for more information on third party Clear GIFs.

 **Third-party advertising and analytics providers.** Ads appearing on the Site may be delivered to users by third-party advertising providers, such as Google. We work with third party advertising providers for purposes such as targeting our advertisements on the Site, and, in doing so we may share with those advertising providers, Non-Personally Identifiable Information about users’ use of the Site.  We use third party advertising and analytics providers, such as Google Analytics, Quantcast, Adroll, Adobe Omniture, SaleCycle, TagMan, ChannelAdvisor, AdChoices, and Exact Target, to collect information about Site usage and users of our site, including demographic and interest-level information. 

Our advertising and analytics providers use cookies and Clear GIFs in order to collect demographic and interest-level information and usage information from users that visit the Site, including but not limited (to information about the pages where users enter and exit the Site, what pages and advertisements users view and visit on the Site, and what items users purchase. Cookies and Clear GIFs allow advertisers and analytics providers to recognize a user when a user visits the Site but also when a user visits other websites. Our advertising and analytics providers use the information they collect from the Site and other web sites to profile users in order to display relevant advertising and to share with us and other web site operators information about users including, but not limited to, age range, gender, geographic regions, general interest and details about devices used to visit web sites and purchase items. We do not link information we receive from our analytics partners with personally identifiable information. 

Specifically, with respect to Google, we use the following Google Analytics advertising features: Display Network Impression Reporting, Google Analytics Demographics and Interest and Remarketing with Google Analytics. For more information regarding Google’s use of cookies and collection and use of information see the [Google Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/). If you would like to opt out of Google Analytics tracking, please visit one of the following links: [Google Ads Preference Manager](https://www.google.com/settings/u/0/ads) or the [Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/).

By clicking on the applicable link below, you may access the privacy policies of other third parties we work with for advertising purposes: 

 **Online tracking and your choices**

As discussed above, we track website usage information through the use of cookies, Clear GIFs, and other tracking mechanisms. We do not observe your browser settings and, even if you select “Do Not Track” options provided by your browser, the Site will still attempt to, and may be successful at, placing cookies and collecting information from your browser. You may still manage the settings on your browser or mobile device and delete and disable cookies and other tracking/recording tools. Doing so may impact your experience using the Site and may make certain features and areas unavailable to you. We do not control third party advertising and analytics providers. You should review their privacy policies for information about whether they honor the “Do Not Track” browser signal. For information about opting-out from Google Analytics tracking, review their privacy policy referenced in the "Third-party advertising and analytics providers section above. Many advertising companies are also members of the NAI or DAA and provide opt-outs on those industry pages at networkadvertising.org/choices and aboutads.info/choices.  

 **Use of information**

 **Generally.** We use your personal information to fulfill orders and to facilitate the Products you purchase or request from us. We use your personal information in the profile we maintain about you, other information we obtain from your current and past activities on the Site, and information we obtain from third parties to: resolve disputes; troubleshoot problems; collect fees owed; measure consumer interest in Products; inform you about online and offline offers, Products, and updates; customize your experience; detect and protect us against error, fraud, and other criminal activity; enforce this Privacy Policy; and as otherwise described to you at the time of collection. We may compare and review your personal information for errors, omissions, and for accuracy.

 **Special offers and updates.** We may occasionally send you information on special deals or promotions. Out of respect for your privacy, you have the option not to receive these types of communications. Please see the "Choice and opt-out" section of this Privacy Policy.

 **Newsletters.** If you wish to subscribe to our newsletters, we will use your name and email address to send the newsletter to you. Out of respect for your privacy, you have the option to unsubscribe from receiving some or all of the newsletters. Please see the "Choice and opt-out" section of this Privacy Policy.

 **Service-related announcements.** We will send you strictly service-related announcements on rare occasions when it is necessary to do so. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, we might send you an email. Generally, you may not opt out of these communications, which are not promotional in nature. If you do not wish to receive them, you have the option to deactivate your account.

 **Customer service.** Based upon the personally identifiable information you provide us, we will send you a welcome email to verify your username and password. We will also communicate with you in response to your inquiries, to provide the services you request, to manage your account and to fulfill your orders.

 **Profile.** We store information that we collect through your stated preferences, cookies, log files, Clear GIFs and third party sources to create a “profile” of your preferences. We may link the Non-Personally Identifiable Information in your profile with an identifier in order to identify you. We do not share your profile with other third parties, other than in aggregate, de-identified form.

 **Non-Personally Identifiable Information.** We may use Non-Personally Identifiable Information for any lawful purpose, including but not limited to analyze trends, administer the Site, track users' movements around the Site, and improve our business and the Site.  

 **Security**

The security of your personal information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information (such as a credit card number) on our registration or order forms, we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us from unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction, both during transmission and once we receive it.

 **Disclosure of information**

 **Generally.** As a matter of policy, we do not sell or rent any of your personal information to third parties for their marketing purposes without first providing you with an opportunity to opt out. However, we may disclose your personal information to our subsidiaries, which are either subject to this Privacy Policy or follow practices at least as protective of your rights as those described in this Privacy Policy. The following sections describe some additional ways that we may disclose your personal information in the normal course of operating our business and providing the Site and Products.

 **Suppliers, developers & partners.** Where you purchase Products from the Site, we may disclose your name, email address, and other information related to your purchase to suppliers or third parties that you select to provide installation services with respect to your purchased Products. This disclosure typically is to enable the supplier or installer to provide support to you, and in certain cases to allow you to benefit from certain levels of support that are only available to registered users. We have no control over what these third parties do with the information that we disclose to them.

 **Agents and service providers.** We may use third parties to provide, on our behalf, to help us operate the Site. For instance, we use credit card processing companies to bill you for Product, and we may use third-party service providers to provide advertising, analytics, and certain fulfillment services for some of our Products. See “Orders and Payment Processing” and “Third party advertising and analytics” above for more information.  We use commercially reasonable efforts to ensure that, except as indicated in this Policy, our agents and service providers do not retain, share, store or use personally identifiable information that we disclose to them to help us operate the Site for any other purposes.

 **Reviews.** Because Reviews are publicly available, we urge you not to submit, as part of any Review, any personally identifiable information or any other information that you do not want to share with anyone else.  If you submit a Review, your User ID will be displayed on any content that your post and will be available to the public. Therefore, if you associate your name with your User ID, your name will be available to the public. Any other information about yourself that you include in such posts will be publicly available.

 **California Minors**

We provide registered users the ability to post information on the Site. If you are a California resident who is under 18 and a registered user of the Site and you are unable to remove content or information you posted in a public area of the Site following the instructions provided on the Site, you may request removal by using the contact information provided in the “Privacy questions” section at the bottom of this Privacy Policy.  When requesting removal you must be specific about the information or content you want remove and provide the URL for each page on the Site where it is located so that we can locate it. 

We are not required to remove any content or information that: (1) federal or state law requires us or a third party to maintain the content or information; (2) the content or information was not posted by you the registered user; (3) we anonymize the content or information so that you cannot be identified; (4) you don’t follow our instructions for removing or requesting removal; or (5) you received compensation or other consideration for providing the content or information.  

REMOVAL OF YOUR POSTED CONTENT OR INFORMATION FROM THE SITE DOES NOT ENSURE COMPLETE OR COMPREHENSIVE REMOVAL OF THAT CONTENT OR INFORMATION FROM OUR SYSTEMS OR THE SYSTEMS OF OUR SERVICE PROVIDERS SUCH AS BAZAARVOICE AND VIVOCHA.  

We are not required to delete the content or information posted by you; our obligations under California law are satisfied so long as we anonymize the content or information or render it invisible to other users and the public.  Also, some content and information you post that has been copied or reposted by a third party is outside of our control and will not be removed. 

 **Legal requests.** We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on us or the Site.

 **Business transition.** In the event we go through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of our assets, we may transfer your personally identifiable information in connection with the business transition.

 **Disclaimer.** We cannot ensure that all of your private communications and other personal information will never be disclosed in ways not otherwise described in this Privacy Policy. By way of example (without limiting the foregoing), we may be required to disclose personal information to the government or third parties under certain circumstances, third parties may unlawfully intercept or access transmissions or private communications, or users may abuse or misuse your personal information that they collect from the Site.

 **Choice / opt-out**

We provide you the opportunity to "opt-out" from receiving marketing materials and offers and promotions.    We provide this “opt-out” when you make your purchase, sign-up for an account, and following the unsubscribe instructions in marketing emails.  You may also “opt-out” from receiving marketing materials and offers and promotions by unsubscribing at: http://tirebuyer.com/unsubscribe.

 **California Shine the Light Law**

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits California residents to request and obtain from us once a year, free of charge, a list of the third parties to whom we have disclosed personal information (as defined under that statute) of that California resident, for direct marketing purposes in the preceding calendar year and the categories of that kind of personal information that was disclosed to them. If you are a California resident and you wish to make such a request you may contact us by using the contact information in the “Privacy questions” section at the bottom of this Privacy Policy.

 **Links to other sites**

This Privacy Policy applies only to information collected by the Site. The Site contains links that take you to other sites or allow you to share information with other sites that are not owned or controlled by us. For example, the Site and emails we send you may include links that will take you directly to a third party site or that will enable you to post information about the Products you purchase on third party social media web sites, such as Facebook. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the terms of use or privacy practices of those other sites. We encourage you to be aware of and read the terms of use and privacy statements of each and every third party web site that may collect your personally identifiable information. 

 **Access to personal information**

If your personally identifiable information changes, or if you no longer desire some or all of our services, you may correct, update, delete, or deactivate your personally identifiable information by making the change on our account information page or by emailing TireBuyer Customer Service from the Contact Us page.

 **Privacy questions  **

If you have questions or concerns about our policies concerning privacy, data collection, data processing, or data transmission, please email TireBuyer Customer Service from the Contact us page. We will respond to your inquiry within 30 days.

TireBuyer.com

601 108th Avenue NE, Suite 420

Bellevue, WA 98004

#### TIREBUYER CUSTOMER REVIEWS

**Great**

It took me forever to find tires. I looked at all of the major competitors and they all seemed to be out of stock especially close to the winter season. I finally looked at TireBuyer.com and sure enough they had my tire in stock and they were delivered in a very timely manner. **I am very satisfied with my purchase and plan on using TireBuyer for my future purchases from here on out. Thanks TireBuyer.**

Reviewed by: Shubs from Ohio
